so what's Jannah
what people think John is something you
can enter you can't John John does your
bracelet
John is the result a mode of being okay
it's the result it's the consequence
yeah Oh we'll get to that
that's what I said there is no I am in
jhana can't say I am in John I'm
entering John I was in China it subsides
for as long as you think John is
something you can't paint it literally
yeah something waiting for you to enter
it that's not junk yeah so is it worth
saying that in the often in the
translations of the Jonas see it says
that one enters upon and dwells in Jonah
doesn't say that in Tommy you know it
says just once well see Jonah having
acquired having a person per day well
yeah yeah couldn't even entity but just
later yes but the point is it's
something that's already based on the
consequence of Jonah of your mode of
being now you know you acquired it no
tell you where that quieted and thus I
entered it and then that's how I dwell
in it which is usually the perception of
it meditation technique object having an
overwhelming experience surge of
pleasure or whatever oh I am to John and
now I am in the Jonathan it's completely
wrong order so I say ah John I miss you
it's more accurate to regard you like
that just basically as I said mode of
being or even becomes your point of view
your new point of view point of view
that doesn't see I am is first
so it's it's a point of view that's that
involves a difference in order yes and
that's a that's a result of certain
contemplations certain understanding
certain development of the mind and if
you wonder which type of development of
the mind just read literally any genre
description it says it clear as a day so
Sir Topham Hatt quite secluded seclusion
from central
there is absolutely no description of
the first channel it does not say that
like that's just one way you can enter
it yeah no it's always Jana is the
result of your seclusion seclusion is
not because of your Jana John is because
seclusion and if you're very doubt about
it it's in the within the same
description is the pleasure yeah the
pleasure of the first John is not of the
first jhana
the pleasure is of the seclusion the
vacations are piti sukha Rebecca John
says the lesson yeah whatever you know
to say it born of solution yes from
sense desire of sensuality and
unwholesome states which pertains to any
any kind of bodily hindrances yeah of
any kind but the common notion is int
jhana then I feel pleasure yeah no
pleasure comes first no pleasure of
jhana but pleasure of seclusion which is where
but pleasure of seclusion which is where
John is which is it at the time that's
what your point of view becomes that's
what your being is there is no room for
I am experienced in this pleasure I'm
entering and how makes it in this John
and whatnot so I mean very clear Polly
yet the entire contemporary notion are
about watching your nostrils
having the ecstatic experience then
stopping thinking stop your thinking of
course and then and then you have this
urge of pleasure and there must have
been Janet so so
the standard idea of Jonathan absorption
involving not thinking you know you
can't hang out here thinking of Jonah
and yet these words Whitaker fujihara
appear Adam main characteristic order
first John so there you get these
strange translations of it's not really
thinking it's like a sustained thought
and a Platt life it's it's literally
thinking we talk of each other always go
together as well and it literally is
just amplifying the same with thinking
with pondering with things going on in
his mind that's the first John doesn't
seek over thinking the first factor with
pondering with the second factor nor is
it the applied that sustained thought in
some sort of concocted method did you do
know it's with thinking in bit pondering
yeah just with with wandering with
roaming about yes and they're not really
different things it's it exactly justice
Stein lead to different aspects I
suppose yeah off your thinking which are
kind of in separate ascending there's
been a synonyms to talk about may be
different extent exactly
yeah so that well that's another
extremely good sure there's notion of my
thinking will stop in the first John is
this experience what I was not aware of
myself yeah not just thinking yeah yet
in imagine 111 yeah every single John is
this absolute clarity of mindfulness yes
as its basis
yeah and brings mindfulness to
discernment is this phenomenon best
fellow on the same exactly exactly see
what what's there to basically it's
imperturbable mindfulness not the
absence of it so how you want to develop
first jhana
seclude yourself from sensuality how can
you secure yourself of sensuality by
understanding the extent of it the
extent of your involvement the extent of
your engagement the basis the necessary
basis for our engagements in charge you
understand that you surmount it having
surmounted it you will know that you've
surmounted it and then that pleasure of
relief of the which is a pleasure the
first jhana will be felt and that's what
first John is the result of that
development basically
so you could see how like even back in
the day Jonah as we discussed before
even in in all their dozens of meant
contemplation investigating even
thinking over pondering some over
something done either virtues of a deity
that you want to develop in yourself or
anything else but the point was you
dwell on it in order to develop it do
you think about it yeah you're not we're
trying to negate the whole idea of
thinking yeah if you want to assume out
your thinking that's the second job and
you can some one second so you're
thinking if you have any relative
problem here you've all you do is go
around denying it
so but Joan has involved a particular
thing yeah I think of Jonathas as
particularly directed mindfulness that's
when you know those other in some other
suitors it's like you can develop Jonah
on the basis of mindfulness of the
corpse yeah we have done on the basis of
mindfulness so the channel ground I
discussed in the census there were
mindfulness of breathing body postures
so it's not it's not an automatic method
it's just way of regarding things on the
basis of miles of Isis mindfulness we're
regarding what sensuality
way off regarding sensuality wherever
you remind yourself the extent of it
that you know you are free from dwell in
that that is the Bliss of the first
jhana that is so as I said like the the
first jhana is not developed by
magically entering and then having
pleasure from it the actual technique
the practice of meditation of the first
jhana is the practice of understanding
the sensual extent yet the extent of
unwholesome that is your practice of
first jhana
that's racism it's impossible to engage
in centrality on the level on the basis
of first jhana that's where the one with
the right view on the basis of first
jhana would be free from sensuality even
when he is not anymore in the first job
because he would have Seabees he would
have been seen clearly its nature of of
actually being repulsive so they're just
to basically come back the idea that you
can not be celibate and not keep the
precepts and have Anantha journals
impossible like a necessary basis for the
like a necessary basis for the
consequence of Jonah Jonah Jonah is
quite secluded from sensual pleasures
quite to remove basically separated
cousin very quite does it indeed indeed
he's separate from it and he's developed
on his fly so separate from from certain
essential states separate from
unwholesome state pleasure arises that
could result to the recognition of that
he cultivates that do anything and
that's how he abides in the first job
and that's what was it he would dwell in
the first jhana having acquired it and
then whether he sits walks extends his
arms goes to the toilet whatever he does
while he dwells in the filter it's
divine because his mind is in the first
John here and that's what timrie harder
to me dwelling doesn't mean temporarily
overwhelmed by something means rich
dwelling so while you're dwelling
in this cootie you eat you drink you lay
down you sit you're doing these things
while you're dwelling in it
it's the same principle of the order of
the job
so more specifically practicing that
more practicing for Gianna which means
practicing with separation from
unwholesome states and sensuality is
done not by tracing down the Central
States but they're seeing a common basis
to all unwholesome states 205 inferences
that's where the five hindrances at the
five they were abandoned in the first
Journal sensuality your will
restlessness laziness distraction doubt
what all of those things have in common
what is the necessary base is necessary
container Dottie
yeah body being there and see even people
body being there and see even people
were to engage with them say you were
all run by hindrance and you give in to
sensuality or an expression available or
whatever you know really leaving the
body you can't even if you want you're
not actually going further into these
things you're just basically increasing
their density so to speak density of the
significance within the same basis
that's why anger is felt bodily
sensualities felt bodily doubt is felt
bothered yeah that's so some people
that's not so obvious that doubt it yeah
but how like how do you know the doubt
is unpleasant yeah it's because you feel
it unpleasantly your body's effect you
can't sleep at night yeah well what's
more bodily than that yeah it's very
bodily so the body is the necessary
basis for for any any of the hindrance
but does that mean that the hindrances
hinder you because of the body
so essentially she cannot be manifest it
cannot be even conceived theoretically
without the base support or anywhere
else except within the basis of alia
Bhatt is that it's in is that it's
hindering aspect
why is it a hundreds in other words it's
a hindrance when when you when you don't
put the body first and when is it that
you don't put the body first there's a
necessary basis for yourself first and
what does that mean in regard to between
you and the body what kind of
relationship is that don't yeah so
that's why again you know comes sort of
being rooted in sense of mind as in
because this body is unknown to me in
any other terms accepted mind that's why
I'm affected by these things do the
bodily yeah and that's when we were
compared to five senses the five bodily
senses the five bodily domains is five
wild animals they have their own
respective domains for feeding yeah you
come possibly sort of going deplete
their food yeah
so they'll starve impossible but you can
stop being appropriate and I can stop
appropriating basically again you also
have no say over their opinions their
preferences know what the animatics yeah
doesn't mean you're not responsible for
giving in to it that's the point yeah
yes that's like am i I likes this the
term denies this
but that on the level of recognition
effect of preference does not mean
automatic engagement with it now now
based on that pool based on this enema
wants to go feed down there I gave in
and I liked it do your data so that's
real responsible for sexuality not for
its arising but it's basically for its
perpetuation for for being for engaging
with it so you hinder yourself yeah by
basically allowing yourself to be
dragged along by presences and how you
allow yourself to be dragged along by
taking the ownership and as you said the
ownership means longboarder as we
discussed in previous talks so which is
the right order then thanks it what is
the what is the order of central pole or
or expression of your world worked out
what is the order
that comes first in many seemingly me
but more specifically oh well it's a
biblical of endurance
okay you see that it's coming first okay
see now I have my mount my mind is
affected by doubt okay so I go around
tonight and I search a night okay fine
because I do all these things together
this is a core of my experience which is
the top and everything that you're doing
is yes yes but with the doubt be
manifested there felt unpleasantly if
the body is not there on its own
beforehand so if you if basically
recognizing marvelous the body recommend
that could be the container of body
without which so what yeah then mindful
is established whereby it doesn't matter
the hindrance yeah you don't pervert the
order and that's how you become quite
secluded from sensuality why because you
have quite removed the the necessary
basis for sensuality to take over you
necessary basis which is that perversion
of that order so now basically so that
is your actions have to have been
purified beforehand as well you'll have
to say no to yourself you have to
practice sense restraint in order then
to discern the necessary basis for those
things if they were to be done and then
you stopped maintaining that basis which
is the wrong order so the hindrances are
now same as belonging to the body that
doesn't belong to you exactly that's
possible let's say yeah which means they don't
let's say yeah which means they don't
hinder you anymore no means they're not
in transition that fully bound up and
contained in rooted in something which
which is about it they fully bound up in
the root in the body and they always
work yeah that's a recognition of that
full understanding that frees you throw
them forever
now just while you're looking at it
initially yeah you have to keep looking
at it to be free from it once you fully
understood hindrance that's what our
hunt is a destroyer of the hindrances so
when when there is sleepiness it's the
body that is sleeping here and the doubt
can never be the fundamental doubt it
can be like oh is this did he say this
so did he say that but none of the doubt
can become the
how used to be could you could you use
feeling as a basis
yeah any any any reference for
mindfulness any mindful in case they're
all contained within feeling yeah of
course sure what the body yeah yeah
no just the reason we're talking about
jhanas that's one of the mother feelings
now okay
john is a particular types of
mindfulness of the body again that's
where the body witness is the one who
has developed yeah the whole the whole
jhana practice yeah
if the same principle show acted those
there is attainment by the body yeah
so it's mindfulness of the body
particularly directed that's how you
practice jhana yeah
in particular direction is the direction
of resolving yeah
so with this be established that the
necessary basis for any hindrance to
hinder you any lost any aversion is you
taking up the body yeah how do you take
up the body what are the means of taking
up the body how is taking up of the body
perpetuated how is it manifesting that's
just the natural state it's just
ignorance that's just thing nobody who
does knees maintenance
another study thing well create a
illusion yeah how are those things
manifested
can you talk about greed hatred greed
hatred and delusion without greedy
hateful deluded acts my body my speech
or my mind can those things be
perpetuated without intention behind it
so you're basically taking up the body
by acting with the body you ask
shouldn't pace with ignorance yeah yeah
ignorant intentions in regard to God so
how do you like to be the body why do
you act like this you act like that so
first you need to start very straining
about it in terms of obvious unwholesome
things yeah
obvious in charity obviously will
obvious distraction obvious unskillful
states precepts some strains no and see
that's the thing now so that's that's
the first way of engagement about it
bodily act doing things with the body
kidney you can have mind raging with
your will or sensuality yeah but if the
body remains there left alone yeah
you're not giving in to the pressure
track with it there is no expression of
that which means whatever unwholesome is
it's not in the domain of the body not
you're not doing it that it could be in
at a later stage all right that's the
second bit so see it's it's kind of more
obvious for people to see okay both the
reactions of bodily and mental actions
are mental yes speech is a type of
converging point in a tween see you have
a verb of thoughts which are not speech
but they are bodily expressed yeah so
how's that possible how is her speech
possible possible you can't speak
without thoughts of speak exactly it's
just inconceivable yet thoughts of
speaking even verbal loud thoughts in
your mind I'm not as discrete because if
there were the speech the Guru has said
that's the speech but he said speech is
when you break into speech physically
that's what constitutes speech so verb
of thinking is not a speech obviously
there isn't speech will ever go thinking
so what's the problem there isn't a
problem there oh yeah something about
generally want assumptions about what's
about speech speech is this generally
assumed to be involve kind of me
breaking out breaking forth yeah boring
yeah out Amil well basically yes the
mind yes so you have three ways of
engaging a body by speech in my mind my
body needs to be restrained beforehand
my mind is too subtle to see directly
but the middle bit the converging point
is where the speech is yeah that's
basically where the assumption takes
about the perversion takes place that's
what color converging point cuz it's see
the speech in itself is physical yeah
sounds after by your mouth it's bottling
it it's also yeah see this body yeah
it's it's very bodily but it's also a
study tonight exactly why so it's it's a
hybrid domain - exactly yeah yeah
and so is the first one to cease by the
way the body doesn't seize up until like
for John anyway that's the gradient the
point is it's another type of engagement
yes with that body see you engage
through physical actions when you assume
your ownership of it when you're
projected to it's pleasure from the
senses you assume pleasure in these
objects why act I get them yeah so
that's already the perversion so you're
basically moving out towards the
pleasure out there with your body yeah
yeah because you assume that to come
first you think the pleasure is over there
you think the pleasure is over there
exactly do you have to engage bodily
with it and body engaging with it is you
accessing that version you getting it
yeah yeah exactly yeah same with the
speech just now
it's not so much into the senses but
it's more between the body and the point
of view between the mind and the body
between the verb of thinking and
pondering and the body yes
okay see you think were like everybody
when you when you speak the whole notion
behind or even before you speak the
notion behind is I have thoughts I have
sentences I have words in my mind I have
the whole voice and then that kind of
flows into the speech out there and it's
the same thing but that's impossible how
can the mental thought flow into the
material body two separate lines
two separate domains there are simple
thing is the present and never never
occurred without each other that's the
root of the confusion not knowing the
nature of that particular Sankara yeah
that's what one breaks into speech so
even when you speak your thoughts can
never become the bodily sounds but
though they have always simultaneous
with it there are no bodily sounds
without thoughts being there present but
sort of phenomenological when you're
when you're speaking that speech sort of
takes the place of your thought see
that's the assumption of Battuta right
okay who hasn't develop jhanas you think
that your speech is taking how can how
can a physical utterance of these sounds
these vibration take place of your
thought how impossible not having fully
discerned that to that extent you still
own and possess to perversion the domain
of the body which is the domain of the
senses fully discern the separated nosov
it inherently impossible to join
together you will then experience the
relief of the pressure of the senses
they were exhibited on the body and that
is the first jhana that's where the
speech will cease in the first jhana
so you want to cultivate that sense the
strength needs to be done first and
maintain throughout of course and then
practice anchoring of your peripheral
awareness as we spoke before as in
recollecting of your mindfulness
recollecting the fact that you are not
speaking while you're thinking verbally
you're cultivating the basically
discernment of the two
simultaneous domains say that it's
separable from each other but you're not
confounding them anymore because you the
exactly speech and the thought that's
why they're like watches Sankara the
determination of your speech because
it's inseparable from it and it's it's
that it's it's not discerning observe me
just take a few hours thinking of Andre
pinky Bob is the determination for
speech thinking about it is anything
kind of speech without yeah okay yeah
there is separate from but see in that
practice of anchoring your mindfulness
in the absence of speech the mouth
that's factually quiet not producing
sound you can then understand the extent
of thinking and pondering yeah without
confusing it for speech because yeah
that's wise silence physical solitude
and not careless chitchat and so on is
absolutely necessary and the Buddha
could have not been like cleared and
have a more hardline stance on it than
he did yeah so thinking that the
thoughts that the speech stands for the
thoughts is the same thing is basically
saying that the thoughts kind of become
speech yeah basically you aren't seeing
the these two separate domains yeah now
you can ask well why is the speech
converging point that's just how things
are that's how the aggregates are
ordered yeah that's not up to you to
decide the fact is it is and for as long
as you're confounding it means it is
ignorance in regard to that entire basis
and whenever there is you know there is
the automatic appropriation so having
sort of distance yourself from sense
desire sensuality
restraint non distraction no careless
projects and little whatever however
meaningfully might present itself no
little activities because all that is
rooted in distraction or sensuality
yesterday yeah unless you can do the
faithfulness thing which is you won't be
doing it so having practice that you
also need to practice physical soldier
it doesn't mean you you like you never
see people you never talk means you talk
only with the purpose the actual purpose
not pressure or need so you cultivate
that like little eyes they would have
said the monks trained himself a little
little speech yeah picking little table
limits on that speech and it's only when
necessary yeah all that is to support
your mindfulness of the factual
recognition it's a form of thought yeah
but it's effectually corrected thought
that you are not speaking yeah see my
mind can be shouting mad but I can
simultaneously through that very fairly
discern that my mouth is not authoring
any sounds thus there is no wrongly
assumed connection between my thought
the moment I forget that I my mouth is
not uttering the sounds I came very well
basically immediately jump back into the
entire form a link yeah it's not being
aware of it it's automatic link it's
automatic sort of mess so to speak
clutter yeah so but once you dwell long
enough that's where you should cultivate
jhanas don't don't be negligent make a
foot discern and so on like it's so many
suitors is because you will become so
familiar with it I guess you can call it
a relationship between them presence of
a mouth able to utter sounds and the
presence of verbal thinking the two
separate domains but you will also then
fully understand that doesn't matter how
careless you are verbal thoughts can
never enter the the extent of speech so
it's always thinking upon during one
breaks into speech and literally two
simultaneous things no other form of
connection any form of connection means form of
any form of connection means form of
misconceiving said then not speaking can
it's like can be the background see this
you're the container whatever you're
thinking about the extent of you
thinking boundary and for as long as you
remain mindful of again and the reason
why you can remain mindful is because
you're not being it you're not unmindful
of my mouth and mindful of a month no
not at all you simply mindful of the
thought that the mouth is not speaking
so it's a negative form of doing yeah
that's why I like if somebody misses
this they might think like Oh mindful of
the sensations in your mouth no that's
just a megadose thinking exactly you can
be mindful of all the sensations and
still cause the confusion between your
thoughts and the domain of speaking
because it's not about what you're
looking at it's about the basis of you
not making any sounds
well there is verbal thinking going on
and so if if you've got like a clear
background this is this the fact that
I'm not speaking to whatever it is I'm
thinking about then that's even a few
laps within that whatever you're
thinking about you can elapse for as
long as you don't start making sound
with your mouth yeah if you're mindful I
said we probably ain't good same with
likely mindfulness of the body posture
doesn't mean how much you forget when
you recollect it usual collect the right
over the poacher hasn't changed the
mouth hasn't spoken yeah if the mouth on
speaking stops speaking and you again
pretty establish the anchor what I was
gonna say was then then it's like that
background of the father I'm not
speaking that provides a background for
the domain of thinking and pondering
other words it basically allows for the
unification of mind it becomes clear
it's a form of unification
you're bats this extensive market
because it's seen against this within
and thinking and pondering
is basically literally the entire extent
from anything from the subtlest thoughts
to the most coarse verbal having a song
repeated in your mind that you can shut
it's all the domain of thinking and
positive and even if you are based on it
thinking about your mouth it appears
pretty much yes it's the extent of the
old in that in that state that's what
you fully understand that any dumber
that manifests in the first jhana is
clearly seen as in all the five
aggregates are clearly seen as not my
not belonging to me that's what first
jhana is the necessary base for the
combination of wisdom often ought to be
enough to be another continue again
clarity of mindfulness because it's the
clarity of imperturbable order that this
is the container of this and it's
inconceivable does matter how much I
forget how careless I get sequency
although that this can become that or
vice versa
yeah the domain of bodily remains the
container of this that's just the way
yeah so that's why you know you can if
your mindfulness is developed to the
extent necessary on account of you know
mindful breathing with - so that doesn't
matter you can then turn that extent of
your mindfulness to the mindfulness of
the converging point of natural body
natural engagements between you and the
body so to speak between the mental and
the physical and mr. Burrage on and then
take you further then from the Buddhist
for the second John I won't dwell into
too much less is it more than enough and
people do something about second jhana
you don't understand what the first is
yeah but from the point of view of the
second jhana
the thinking and pondering is the
physical is the container
yeah
within which unified mind that doesn't
yeah that's where second John is called
noble silence by the way not the first
job first jhana you can't speak yeah but
that's not another silence that was the
silence is when the mind stopped
speaking is well so yeah you want to
stop thinking you gotta stop speaking
with your mind which is the second
journal and you won't get there until
you get the first one and you won't get
the first one for as long as you think
you can get it that's a thing you can
get it by cultivating the basis for it
intensifies it's a consequence exactly
that's why if it were not consequence it
would be something you're doing yes and
then we're gonna say like all you you
can't say in John I am entering the
fridge and I'm practicing the physician
I'm obtaining the first John I'm leaving
the first John yeah yeah things Johnny
you can't say that doesn't mean you're
not aware of anything that's not the
reason why you can't say you can't say
cuz it's you know doing it it's result
of things you've done such as semantic
sensuality anchoring your peripheral
recollected nacinda fact that factually
mouth is abstaining not speaking not
patterning sounds and it's been doing so
for a while that's why you know like
having having been secluded from
sensuality essential pleasure joy from
seclusion arises one by the Jonah having
acquired it doesn't mean you know as I
said before like maybe took you a whole
month to summon the sensual domain
before then the result of your binding
in that state becomes the Jannah or he
can take you half a day sometimes more
sometimes on depending how careless you
were if you were careless
that's what once you cultivate it long
enough it's done it will as the suitors
would say and again it's not see when
you know whenever they would say oh I
don't I don't need all of this because
whoever can obtain John as it will like
we're maha kassapa said that for example
I don't need all these luxuries oh yeah
Chris why we can obtain John as it will
he's like the greatest basically yeah
he's saying that as a matter of fact in
the reason why there is a praise oh you
can obtain John as it will you
because he done all the work like you
wouldn't what my human mind would take
praise on account of anything but as a
rational mind mind that is authentic
would recognize well there is a praise
of random things that you're nothing to
do yes oh look how tall you are
I'm not saying that but look how
virtuous you are look how well kind of
men adored well read or intelligent
reasonable you are could you media and
that is a legitimate price because you
invested Janus is the utmost effort you
can make in that sense that's what's the
best place whoever can tell me the world
means not he was lucky to get them means
he done so such an extent of this
anchoring mindfulness proper work bit
literally it will everything is there
now because she just you know we won the
jackpot and he just happens to him oh
he's so lucky why would you place that
yeah you're lucky and nothing to do in
here cycling anchoring your mindfulness
in the recognition of a mouth that is
not uttering sounds
there is a converging point mind you
when it comes to speech writing typing
all those would be means of physical
convergent of your expression yeah but
chief of them is the math and that's so
again sexuality is inherently
inseparable from the notion of your
mouth as well second it's the first
point of engagement with sensuality when
you're a toddler breastfeeding eating
it's the first point of satisfaction and
it always remains like as I said your
sensuality can proliferate your
preferences can proliferate the
expression of your real world can
proliferate fundamentally it's all still
within the mouth just its density keeps
increasing the more you engage with it
but it cannot become anywhere else
except from the container of the mouth
because that's the first point of
engagement with the body the first point
of confusion so disappearance between
mind and body mind is their body is
there yet for you mouth is kind of
settings to the mental and pertains to
physical how's that possible not fully
clarifying that that's how you own both
or doesn't get affected by both and
again that's why the recognition of that
that is actually impossible it's
inconceivable for does matter how burb
of thinking is it's inconceivable for it
to become the sounds from your mouth
yeah the way it happens is just on this
level on this two simultaneous levels
yeah that's where you fully understand
that doesn't mean what kind of thoughts
you had are threatening fearful you will
not be afraid you know Francis because
you realize oh that's where this is
manifested and it's actually consumed
and so now that's going back to so same
we know will vibrate restrains
so not to we were told you talked about
positive restraint
you know having it having thoughts of
ill-will safer just making sure that you
don't do anything but now use sort of my
driving the how to restrain yourself on
a verbal level exactly which then
restrains your mind the only reason your
mind was not restrained is because he
was under the assumption yeah that it
can pertain to that which concerns me
which is the external world of the
senses well you realize the mind can
never step into it nor can it become the
line otherwise it is physical mental
yeah bodily and and on the level of the
mind yes sure fundamentally it's all mental
yes sure fundamentally it's all mental
in terms of its Aldama manifesting
itself but that's a different approach
this is the approach of Jonah which is
about understanding this converging
point between points of engagement with
the body which is our necessary basis
for any centrality to affect you to
pressure it pertain to you so when that
order becomes uncorruptible by your
ignoring by your carelessness you know
you aren't you you are abiding in that
which you've acquired which is the right
order which is where John is
that's where they're always wholesome
you can't have unwholesome John
impossible because I'm wholesomeness is
defined as we said before in other talks
by the perversion of the order that's a
definite that's why I'm all some things
that are also because they contain a
contradiction repulsive as attractive
in Jannah that's impossible that's why
it's impossible for them to be
unwholesome and so again in first John
so he said at the beginning that
overcoming sensuality involves putting
the body first recognizing not putting
me first to sing-sing that it is first
seeing was the first assuming itself
yeah it's an essay and not like first
initially and then changing it remains
first yeah there's a match the extent of
central pressure in a jewelry always
account nothing within that you discern
even a more specific manifestation or
that order of the body and body first
which is through math yeah and your
thoughts yeah that's still that because
that's exactly what central is the
container body and the thoughts yeah in
regard to everything to the body can go
through rather than the usual kind of I
use my body or hi exact
so the only way that that mindfulness of
presently enduring non-speaking now the
only way that can become intelligible is
on the basis of that a sense restraint
yeah celibacy we draw from sensuality girl
celibacy we draw from sensuality girl
will that's I get to understand all the
other hindrances as well you see that
doesn't matter how much sleeping is
restlessness might be like how heavy it
might be you won't be bearing their
weight for as long as you don't the very
order or what comes first which is the
body so this is what do you want it or
not it cannot be anywhere else except on the
it cannot be anywhere else except on the
body the domain